时间索引：01:30 /// 什么是亚轨道飞行
05:50 /// 维珍银河的太空船二号
12:45 /// 蓝色起源的新谢泼德
20:50 /// 并排比较
24:45 /// 总结
Hi, it's me Tim Dodd the everyday astronaut.
嗨 我是 Tim Dodd 每日宇航员
The time has arrived.
时间已经到了
We're at the start of a new era of human spaceflight.
我们正处于人类太空飞行的新时代的起点
原视频名：Blue Origin VS Virgin Galactic // How do they compare
原作者名：Everyday Astronaut
视频来源：youtu.be/kxAkK8oCewM
原视频发布日期：20210710
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
Commercial suborbital rides to the edge of space.
商业亚轨道飞行到太空的边缘
And what's crazy is
而疯狂的是
there isn't just one company doing this,
并非只有一家公司在做这件事
but two companies are entering service at almost the exact same time.
而是两家公司几乎在同一时间开始服务
Of course, we're talking about Richard Branson's Virgin Galactic and their SpaceShipTwo space plane
当然 我们谈论的是理查德·布兰森的维珍银河和他们的太空船二号太空飞机
and Jeff Bezos's Blue Origin with their New Shepard vehicle.
和杰夫·贝佐斯的蓝色起源的新谢泼德火箭
And what's exciting is that
而令人振奋的是
each of these guys decided to ride on the very first crewed flights of their company's rockets.
这两位创始人都决定参加他们公司火箭的首次载人飞行
Both of these systems are capable of giving customers an incredible once in a lifetime experience,
这两个系统都能够给客户带来一生中不可思议的体验
taking them to the edge of space and back
将他们带到太空的边缘并返回
providing them with approximately four minutes of weightlessness
为他们提供大约4分钟的失重状态
and a view less than 600 humans have ever seen well for now.
以及目前不到600名人类所见过的景色
So today let's do a little overview of what exactly suborbital spaceflight is,
因此 今天让我们对亚轨道航天飞行做一个小小的概述
what you could expect on one of these rides,
你可以在这些旅程中期待些什么
and then go over each system,
然后再来看看每个系统
comparing them side by side for the ultimate rundown.
并对每个系统进行比较 以了解最终的情况
时间索引：01:30 /// 什么是亚轨道飞行
05:50 /// 维珍银河的太空船二号
12:45 /// 蓝色起源的新谢泼德
20:50 /// 并排比较
24:45 /// 总结
So here's the timestamps for each section.
所以这里是每个部分的时间戳
We also have links in the description.
我们在视频简介中也有章节链接
The YouTube play bar is broken up into these sections
油管的播放栏被分成了这些部分
and we have an article version of this video up at everydayastronaut.com.
同时我们在everydayastronaut.com上有这个视频的文章版本
Okay, let's get started.
好 让我们开始吧
- [Mission Control] Three, two, one,
-  [任务控制]三 二 一
and liftoff!
起飞
- [Neil] That's one small step for man.
-  [尼尔]这是对人类的一小步
- [Mission Control] That's Houston contact for the test one.
-  [任务控制]这是休斯敦和一号测试的通信
Suborbital commercial spaceflight.
亚轨道商业太空飞行
什么是亚轨道飞行
Now you might be familiar with the first operational commercial spaceflight from the United States in 2020,
那么你可能对2020年美国的首次商业航天飞行感到熟悉
when SpaceX took Bob Behnken and Doug Hurley up to the International Space Station
那时 SpaceX将鲍勃·本肯和道格·赫尔利送上了国际空间站
for NASA on their Crew Dragon spacecraft,
这次任务是为NASA执行的 使用了SpaceX的载人龙飞船
riding a Falcon 9 rocket.
搭载在猎鹰9号火箭上
Well, that was an orbital mission called DM2 or Demonstration Mission 2.
恩 那是一个被称为DM2或验证任务2的轨道级任务
And that's a completely different task than what Blue Origin and Virgin Galactic are doing for now.
而这与蓝色起源和维珍银河目前正在做的任务完全不同
An orbital mission requires a huge rocket,
一个轨道任务需要一枚巨大的火箭
and once it gets its payload into orbit,
一旦它将其有效载荷送入轨道
that payload is not going to come back down until it de-orbits,
该有效载荷在脱离轨道之前是不会回来的
which could be months and months or years.
这可能是几个月或几年
Suborbital spaceflight doesn't reach orbit.
亚轨道航天飞行并没有到达轨道
They're just exactly that suborbital less than orbit,
确切地说 他们只是亚轨道 少于 轨道
but these rockets aren't trying to get to orbit.
但这些火箭并不尝试进入轨道
They're purpose-built space tourism machines.
它们是专门建造的太空旅游机器
So if you're poking fun of these rockets for not reaching orbit,
因此 如果你取笑这些火箭没有到达轨道
that'd be like poking fun of a Honda Civic for not being able to pull as much as a semi-truck.
那就像取笑本田思域不能像半挂卡车那样能拉货一样
It's not designed to do that.
设计上 它就不是用来干这活的
So by poking fun of a Civic's towing capacity,
那么 取笑思域的牵引能力这件事
it really speaks to more about your lack of knowledge than it does the Civic's lack of a towing capacity.
与其说是对思域缺乏牵引能力的批评 倒不如说是你缺乏知识的表现
But the important thing here is these rides do go to space.
但重要的是 这些旅程确实能上太空
I mean, after all to go to space, you just go up until there's virtually no atmosphere,
我是指 毕竟要去太空 你只需上升到几乎没有大气层的地方
and it's not like the atmosphere just suddenly stops,
而且这并不是说大气层突然就没了
it just slowly fades away
它只是慢慢地消失
until you've hit an altitude where there's just pretty much no atmosphere.
直到你到达一个几乎没有大气的高度
Like when you drive a car up a tall mountain.
就像你把车开上一座高山
It's not like, oh, all of a sudden the air is thin.
这并不是说 哦 突然间空气就稀薄了
It just gets thinner and thinner, the higher and higher up you go.
空气只是随着高度增加而变得稀薄
Keep going with that idea
带着这个想法继续前进
and you reach a point where there's just virtually zero atmosphere
你就会到达一个大气几乎消失的位置
and that my friends is space.
而老兄啊 那就是太空
So space is really just a lack of atmosphere,
因此 太空实际上只是缺乏大气
but it's not a lack of gravity similar to air.
但它并不像(缺乏)空气那样缺乏重力
It's not like you get up to space
不是说你到了太空中
and gravity is just suddenly turned off and you just stay floating there.
同时重力突然被关闭 你就一直漂浮在那里
As a matter of fact, when you are at 100 kilometers in altitude,
事实上 当你在100km的高度上时
you're still being pulled by earth with nearly the same amount of force as you would be at sea level.
你仍然被地球拉着 其力量几乎与你在海平面上的力量相同
Specifically, gravity still pulls you at 9.4 meters per second squared of acceleration,
具体来说 重力仍然以9.4m/s²的加速度拉着你
as opposed to the 9.8 meters per second squared here at sea level.
而在海平面上是9.8m/s²
But you'll actually start experiencing weightlessness the moment the engine shuts down,
但实际上 在发动机关闭的那一刻 你将开始体验到失重的感觉
which is only about halfway up your climb to space.
而这大概只在你前往太空的路途上的一半位置
That's right, even though you're still going up,
没错 尽管你仍然在上升
you and the spacecraft are both no longer accelerating.
你和航天器都不再加速了
You're coasting up experiencing zero G or weightlessness,
你是在经历零重力或失重的情况下滑行上升
kind of like the peaks of a roller coaster
有点像过山车的峰顶
where you feel like you're leaving your seat for a little bit.
你会在那里感觉有点离开了座位
That's a brief moment of weightlessness.
那是一个短暂的失重时刻
This is basically that, but you'll experience it for a long time,
基本上就是这样 但会经历很长一段时间
all the way from engine shutoff up through your peak altitude or apogee.
从发动机关闭到峰值高度 或者说远地点的整个过程中
And even as you fall,
甚至在坠落时也是如此
until you finally begin to experience deceleration from atmospheric drag.
直到你最终开始经历大气阻力的减速度
The fact that your spacecraft is slowing down is what will push you back into your seat.
在航天器正在减速的时候 其会把你推回座位
Now we should point out these vehicles are just basically going straight up.
那么我们应该指出 这些航天器基本上是直着上升的
At apogee, they have virtually zero horizontal velocity.
在远地点 它们的水平速度几乎为零
They're more or less completely stationary for a brief moment in time.
基本上会在一段短暂的时间内完全静止
If they were to try to stay in space by getting into orbit,
如果它们试图通过入轨而留在太空中
they would need to be traveling at orbital velocities.
那么它们得以轨道速度飞行
So roughly 28,000 kilometers an hour sideways.
因此 得达到大约7.8km/s的横向速度
That's about eight times faster than their peak velocities during ascent.
这比它们在上升过程中的峰值速度快了大约八倍
youtu.be/352P0sLMnsw
If you want a quick run down on orbit versus sub orbit, check this video out.
如果你想快速了解轨道与亚轨道的关系 请看这个视频
The Karman line is a common definition of the edge of space and is defined as 100 kilometers.
太空边缘的一个常见定义是卡门线 定义一般是离地100km高度的位置
Although most would argue that 80 kilometers is just as much in space as 100 kilometers.
虽然大多数人会认为 80km和100km的太空是一样的
So there are actually some considerations
因此 实际上有一些考虑
to changing all international definitions of spaces, altitude to 80 kilometers.
去改变所有国际定义中的太空 将其改为80km的海拔高度
That being said until that number changes,
既然如此 在这个数字改变之前
only one of these two rockets will actually get you above the Karman line or 100 kilometers.
这两枚火箭中只有一枚能真正让你超过卡门线或100km
Which one is it?
是哪一个呢？
Well for that, let's dive into each system.
恩 为此 让我们深入了解每个系统
维珍银河的太空船二号
First up, let's talk about Richard Branson's Virgin Galactic.
首先 让我们来谈谈理查德·布兰森的维珍银河
Virgin Galactic is a suborbital tourism launch company.
维珍银河是一家亚轨道旅游发射公司
Now don't confuse this with Virgin Orbit,
现在不要把它与维珍轨道混淆
who is a small sat rocket company
维珍轨道是一家(发射)小型卫星的运载火箭公司
who launches their LauncherOne rocket from a Boeing 747.
他们从波音747飞机上发射发射器一号火箭
Now at one point they both were part of Virgin Galactic, but now they're separate entities.
那么维珍轨道曾经是维珍银河的一部分 但现在从中独立出来了
Virgin Galactic currently has one system composed of SpaceShipTwo
维珍银河目前有一个由太空船二号组成的系统
and its carrier plane WhiteKnightTwo.
和其运载飞机白骑士二号组成
Just to mitigate some confusion here,
只是为了澄清一些事实
there is also a newer production ready version called SpaceShip III.
还有一个较新的可用于生产的版本 称为太空船三号
It's virtually the same thing as two,
它与二号几乎是一样的东西
and it hasn't flown as of the making of this video.
但在制作这段视频时 它还没有飞起来
So from here on out, I'm just going to refer to the vehicle as SpaceShipTwo.
那么从这里开始 我只把该航天器称为太空船二号
SpaceShipTwo and WhiteKnightTwo are scaled up versions of the original SpaceShipOne and WhiteKnightOne.
太空船二号和白骑士二号是最初太空船一号和白骑士一号的放大版本
And now those were built by Scaled Composites
那么这些都是由缩尺复合建造的
and won the 2004 Ansari X prize of $10 million
并赢得了2004年安萨里X大奖的1000万美元奖金
by successfully flying to space and back twice in just five days.
也就是在短短五天内成功飞往太空并返回两次
But it was just after their first powered flight to space
但就在他们第一次进行有动力飞行到太空之后
that Virgin Galactic announced they'd licensed the technology and sponsor SpaceShipOne,
维珍银河就宣布他们已经获得技术许可 并赞助了太空船一号
and then they would start building their own bigger versions for space tourism.
然后开始为太空旅游建造他们自己的更大的版本
So Virgin Galactic, co-founded the Spaceship Company in 2005 at a 70% ownership
因此 维珍银河 在2005年与缩尺复合共同创建了太空船公司 拥有70%的所有权
with Scaled Composites owning 30%.
而缩尺复合拥有30%的所有权
The spaceship company's goal was to scale up the SpaceShipOne and its carrier plane
这个太空船公司的目标是扩大太空船一号及其运载飞机的规模
to maximize their commercial spaceflight potential.
以最大限度地发挥其商业航天的潜力
In 2008, the company would roll out their new WhiteKnightTwo carrier plane,
2008年 该公司推出他们新的白骑士二号运载飞机
which was about three times larger than the original WhiteKnight.
比原来的白骑士大大约三倍
It features a full twin fuselage with four jet engines.
它有一个完整的双机身 有四台喷气发动机
What's cool about this is one of the fuselage is actually a replica of SpaceShipTwo's interior.
最酷的是 其中一个机身实际上是太空船二号内部的复制品
So they can train passengers at a very reasonable cost.
所以他们可以以非常合理的成本来培训乘客
And the other fuselage can be used for cheaper trips to 18 kilometers,
而另一个机身可以用来进行更便宜的旅行 高度达到18km
almost double that of a standard airliner,
几乎是标准客机的两倍
which is high enough to be able to see the dark blue sky.
这个高度足以让人看到深蓝色的天空
The first SpaceShipTwo or technically the first Scaled Composites model 339 SpaceShipTwo
第一艘太空船二号 或者严格来说是第一艘缩尺复合339型太空船二号
was revealed on December 7th, 2009.
于2009年12月7日曝光
And it was named VSS Enterprise.
它被命名为VSS企业号
It sported a much larger design capable of two pilots and six passengers,
它采用了更大的设计 能够容纳两名飞行员和六名乘客
but it shares many similarities with the first spaceship vehicle.
但它与第一艘太空船有许多相似之处
On ascent, it features an upgraded version of their unique hybrid rocket engine.
在上升过程中 它采用了他们那独特的固液混合火箭发动机的升级版
The engine uses HTPB rubber-based solid rocket fuel,
该发动机使用HTPB橡胶基固体火箭燃料
but unlike a traditional solid rocket booster, it can be shut down mid flight.
但与传统的固体火箭助推器不同 它可以在飞行中关机
This is where the hybrid comes from.
这就是混合动力的由来
The solid rocket propellant will only remain firing
固体火箭推进剂只有在以下情况下才会保持燃烧
when liquid or gaseous nitrous oxide are present in the motor.
也就是液态或气态的一氧化二氮存在于发动机中时
So the pilots can light the engine with an igniter
因此 飞行员可以用一个点火器点燃发动机
and then nitrous flows from an oxidizer tank into the solid propellant.
然后一氧化二氮从氧化剂罐流向固体推进剂
As long as the nitrous is flowing, the rocket will continue to run,
只要一氧化二氮在流动 火箭就会继续运行
but shutting off the supply will shut the engine down.
但关闭氧化剂供应将关闭发动机
That's super cool.
这真是超级酷
Despite being able to turn the engine on and off, it cannot actively throttle.
尽管能够开启和关闭发动机 但它不能主动节流
It is a fixed thrust output.
它的推力输出是固定的
For a bit of time at Virgin Galactic played around with a different solid fuel
在一段时间里 维珍银河使用一种不同的固体燃料进行了试验
called thermoplastic polyamide with nitrous
称为聚酰胺热塑性弹性体 而氧化剂使用一氧化二氮
and a little methane for combustion and helium for shutdown.
以及一点甲烷用于燃烧 氦气用于关机
But they would switch back to HTPB following the first and only flight with that new engine,
但他们在第一次也是唯一一次使用这种新发动机的飞行后 又转回了HTPB
which unfortunately wound up with the loss of the vehicle and the tragic loss of one of the two test pilots.
不幸的是 这次两名试飞员的飞行最终损失了航天器和一名试飞员
But the breakup of the space plane had nothing to do with this new engine.
但是太空飞机的解体与这个新发动机没有关系
空中浩劫S18E06
The breakup actually had to do with a staple of its design, the feathered re-entry system.
解体实际上与它的设计中的一个主要部分有关 即羽翼再入系统
This happened when one of the test pilots accidentally prematurely unlocked the feathering system
这件事发生在其中一名试飞员不小心过早地解锁了羽翼系统
resulting in the vehicle breaking up at supersonic speeds while still under powered flight.
导致航天器在超音速动力飞行时解体
Now, obviously they fixed that
现在 很明显他们解决了这个问题
and made it so it's impossible for that system to prematurely activate,
并使其不能过早地启动该系统
but overall, the shape of the space plane is super unique and has stayed basically the same
但总的来说 太空飞机的形状是超级独特的 基本上保持不变
and features those pneumatically tilted tails and horizontal stabilizers.
并带有那些倾斜的气动尾翼和水平稳定面
The twin tails of the rocket plane have what they call a carefree re-entry profile,
火箭飞机的双尾翼具有他们所说的简易再入外形
which takes inspiration from a badminton shuttlecock.
它的灵感来自于羽毛球
This is a passively stable design that provides a large amount of drag
这是一种被动稳定的设计 可以提供大量的阻力
and makes the vehicle want to re-enter belly down each time.
并使航天器每次都倾向于机腹向下再入
Even if it, for some reason, began to re-enter upside down.
即使它由于某种原因 开始反向再入(也能调整过来)
Once the vehicle is subsonic and then the lower portions of the atmosphere,
一旦航天器进入亚音速 然后进入大气层的低层部分
it straightens its wings back out
它的机翼就会伸直回位
and glides back to the runway for a fairly standard landing.
并滑行回到跑道上 进行相当标准的降落
Or you might notice it's missing a front wheel
或者你可能会注意到它缺少一个前轮
and instead it uses a simple skid that acts like a brake pad on touchdown.
相反的是 它使用了一个简单的防滑装置 在触地时起着类似刹车片的作用
It's really interesting about this vehicle is that humans are 100% in control.
这个航天器真正有趣的地方在于 其由乘员100%控制
I think it's super impressive that these are fully flown by skilled pilots.
我觉得其完全由熟练的飞行员来驾驶这一点 超级令人印象深刻
That's right. There is no autopilot.
没错 没有自动驾驶
There's not even fly by wire.
甚至没有电传飞控
The pair of pilots control the vehicle
两名飞行员是这样控制航天器的
directly through either electronically controlled trim at supersonic speeds
在超音速状态下通过电子配平装置
or cables and rod linkages at subsonic speeds.
或在亚音速时通过钢丝和连杆控制
It's kind of crazy to me that such a beautiful 21st century spacecraft also so old school.
这样一个21世纪的美丽航天器也如此老派 对我来说有点疯狂
I actually kind of love that.
我实际上有点喜欢这一点
In space, they have some cold gas thrusters to control orientation outside the atmosphere.
在太空中 配有冷气推进器来控制大气层外的姿态
Cold gas thrusters are just compressed air and are very simple and effective.
冷气推进器只是压缩空气 非常简单而有效
They can control each axis of the vehicle.
可以控制航天器的每个轴
So pitch yaw and roll.
也就是 俯仰 偏航和滚转
And there's a pair of each thruster for redundancy.
而且为了冗余 每个推进器都有一个备份
One of the coolest things about this vehicle is Virgin Galactic's attention to detail for the passengers.
这个航天器最酷的地方之一是维珍银河对乘客搭乘细节的关注
They've done an amazing job, making sure the customer experience is top notch,
他们做了一项了不起的工作 以确保客户的体验是一流的
like by using 16 cameras on board.
例如 在飞机上使用16个相机
So you don't have to fiddle with your own camera,
这样你不必摆弄你自己的相机
which can help you live in the moment.
这样就可以好好感受此刻的体验
These beautiful seat back displays to help you stay up to date with every portion of the flight.
这些漂亮的座椅背面显示屏 帮助你随时了解飞行的每一部分
The seats are also dynamic
座椅也是可动态调整的
and set their angle to maximize comfort and safety at all different portions of flight.
其角度可根据不同的飞行过程进行设置 尽量提高舒适性和安全性
And the 17 windows all have a halo edge,
而且17个窗户都有一个晕边
so you can easily grab onto them to maximize your viewing experience.
这样你就可以很容易地抓住它们 最大化观看体验
Something that I think is extremely important.
我认为这一点极为重要
In 2016, Virgin Galactic built their second SpaceShipTwo called VSS unity,
2016年 维珍银河建造了他们的第二艘太空船二号 名为VSS团结号
which flew three times to space before being ready for passengers.
在三次飞往太空之后 才开始搭乘乘客
And that's what's flying currently.
而这就是现役的太空船二号
And on March 30th, 2021, Virgin Galactic showed off their first spaceship three called VSS Imagine.
而在2021年3月30日 维珍银河展示了他们的第一艘太空船三号 名为VSS想象号
So that's the rundown on Virgin Galactic's SpaceShipTwo.
那么 这就是维珍银河的太空船二号的情况介绍
At the end, we'll compare its exact specs to Blue Origin's New Shepard,
在视频的最后 我们会把它的具体规格与蓝色起源的新谢泼德号进行比较
but first let's do a rundown on that vehicle too.
但首先让我们也对新谢泼德做一个概述
蓝色起源的新谢泼德
Jeff Bezos's Blue Origin has been around for a very long time.
杰夫·贝索斯的蓝色起源已经存在了很长时间
In fact was founded before SpaceX way back in 2000.
事实上 它创建得比SpaceX早 在2000年就成立了
Blue Origin's philosophy is Gradatim Ferociter,
蓝色起源的理念是Gradatim Ferociter
latin for step-by-step ferociously
在拉丁语中的意思是一步步凶猛地发展
and their slow and patient approach to spaceflight development certainly shows that.
而他们缓慢而耐心的航天发展方式无疑表明了这一点
Before New Shepherd saw the light of day,
在新谢泼德出现之前
Blue Origin was demonstrating many technologies with a rocket powered vehicle named Goddard in 2006.
2006年 蓝色起源用一个名为戈达德的火箭动力航天器验证了许多技术
After Goddard, Blue Origin began developing the New Shepard system,
在戈达德之后 蓝色起源开始开发新谢泼德系统
which is a space capsule and a booster.
它由一个太空舱和一个助推器构成
New Shepard is named after Alan Shepard,
新谢泼德是以艾伦·谢泼德命名的
the first American in space who performed a suborbital flight.
他是第一个在太空中进行亚轨道飞行的美国人
Their next rocket New Glenn is named after John Glenn,
他们的下一枚火箭新格伦是以约翰·格伦命名的
who was the first American to go on an orbital flight.
他是第一个进行轨道飞行的美国人
So as the name suggests that rocket will be orbital.
因此 正如其名所示 该火箭将是轨道级的
But back to New Shepherd.
但回到新谢泼德
The capsule was tested at the end of 2012
其太空舱在2012年底进行了测试
with a pad escape test of their launch abort system
也就是对发射中止系统进行的发射场逃逸测试
demonstrating their pusher, solid rocket motor abort system,
验证了他们的推进器 也就是固体火箭发动机中止系统
and the ability to fully deploy the parachutes for a soft landing at a low altitude.
以及完全展开降落伞在低空软着陆的能力
You may have noticed what looks like a large center console in the middle of the spacecraft.
你可能已经注意到 在航天器的中间有一个看起来像大型中央控制台的东西
Well, that's not just a table or something.
恩 那不只是一张桌子或其他东西
That's actually a solid rocket motor
那实际上是一个固体火箭发动机
capable of pushing the capsule away from a failed booster in a hurry,
能够将太空舱从失效的助推器上迅速推离
aiding in the safety considerations of the vehicle.
有助于增加航天器的安全性
In 2015 Blue Origin announced they had completed acceptance testing of their BE-3 engine.
2015年 蓝色起源宣布他们已经完成了BE-3发动机的验收测试
That would be at the heart of the New Shepard booster.
这将是新谢泼德助推器的核心
The BE-3 is a combustion tap-off cycle hydrolox powered engine.
BE-3是一个抽气循环液氢液氧发动机
The tap-off cycle is pretty unique.
抽气循环是相当独特的
It's where you basically just punch a hole in your combustion chamber
基本上只是在燃烧室上打一个洞
and let some of the internal pressure of the main combustion chamber
并让主燃烧室的一些内部压力
spin the turbine to power your pumps.
来旋转涡轮机 为泵提供动力
It's definitely a bit of a head-scratcher when it comes to, how does it run?
它的运行原理实在让人有点头疼
I mean like how do you even start an engine that has the combustion chamber running the pumps
我的意思是 燃烧室驱动泵的发动机是如何启动的
and the pumps are running the engine and then the engines running the pumps.
看起来是泵在运行发动机 之后发动机又在运行泵
I mean, yeah, well, we'll save that for another video.
我的意思是 是的 好吧 我们将把这个问题留给另一个视频
What I like about the BE-3 is that they've kind of split it out inefficiently on the base of the New Shepard.
我喜欢BE-3的地方是 其组件在新谢泼德的底部有点被低效地分割开来
So although the packaging isn't tight and it's probably not very mass efficient,
因此 尽管模块并不严密 而且可能并不节省质量
it is much easier to access all of the parts and potentially tweak or repair when necessary.
但更容易接触到所有的部件 并在必要时进行调整或维修
This allows them to quickly refurbish and then learn the engine quite literally inside and out.
这使他们能够快速翻新 然后完全地了解发动机
Meanwhile, they can help use this knowledge to shape their BE-3U
同时 他们可以利用这些知识来塑造他们的BE-3U
vacuum optimized, open expander cycle version,
这是一台真空优化 开式膨胀循环的版本
and that's going to be used on their New Glenn orbital rocket in the future.
这将被用于他们未来的新格伦轨道级火箭
The BE-3 powers the rocket from their West Texas launch site at about 1200 meters above sea level,
BE-3为火箭提供动力 从他们西德克萨斯海拔约1200米的发射场
all the way up to about 50 kilometers or so when the vehicle hits main engine cutoff,
一路上升到大约50km左右 在那里 火箭主发动机关机
and then it's going to coast up the rest of the way to space.
然后 它将在剩下的时间滑行至太空
80 seconds before apogee, the vehicle stages into its two separate components,
在抵达远地点前80秒 航天器分级成两个独立的部分
the booster and the capsule.
助推器和太空舱
The capsule will re-enter and fall back down slower than the booster,
太空舱再入和落下的速度比助推器慢
which is skinnier with less surface area.
(因为)相对来说 助推器的表面积(投影面积)较小 比较瘦
And here's where the booster does something.
而在这里 助推器就会做一些事
I think that we all just simply love to see.
我认为 我们都乐见其成的事情
On the way down it deploys fins to help steer it.
在下降的过程中 它会展开翼面来控制姿态
Then it deploys some air brakes to help scrub off velocity.
然后展开一些阻力板来减慢速度
Then when only about three kilometers above the ground,
然后 在离地面只有大约3km的时候
it lights up it's BE-3 engine to propulsively land.
点燃了BE-3发动机进行反推式着陆
One impressive thing about their engine is
关于BE-3令人印象深刻的一点是
it can actually throttle down below 20% of maximum thrust,
其可将节流阀减少到最大推力的20%以下
which can allow the rocket to hover and then perfectly redirect itself over its targeted landing area.
这可以让火箭悬停 然后在目标着陆区上空完美地调整方向
For reference, SpaceX's Merlin engine on their Falcon 9 and Heavy can throttle down to about 40%,
作为参考 SpaceX的猎鹰9号和重型猎鹰上的梅林发动机可将节流阀降低到大约40%
当然，火箭的干质比也是很重要的，新谢泼德助推器的干质比比猎鹰9号的一级低
which is also why the Falcon 9 can't actually hover
这也是猎鹰9号实际上不能悬停的原因
and has to do a fairly aggressive hover slam maneuver.
而必须做一个相当凶猛的悬停猛击机动
But a fun little fact here,
但这里有一个有趣的小事实
Blue Origin's New Shepard actually became the first rocket to reach space and then propulsively land.
蓝色起源的新谢泼德实际上成为了第一个到达太空并进行反推式着陆的火箭
They did this about one month before SpaceX landed their first Falcon 9 booster.
在SpaceX着陆第一个猎鹰9号助推器之前的一个月就做到了这一点
Now of course, one of these rockets is suborbital, reaching a peak velocity of about 3500 kilometers an hour
那么 当然 新谢泼德是亚轨道火箭 峰值速度在1km/s左右
while traveling mostly straight up with virtually no horizontal velocity at all.
而大部分时间是直线上升 几乎没有水平速度
And the other rocket Falcon 9 is an orbital rocket booster
而另一枚火箭猎鹰9号是一个轨道级火箭助推器
traveling at up to 8000 kilometers an hour sideways,
横向速度可高达2km/s左右
while carrying a large upper stage about the size of the entire New Shepherd vehicle.
其大型上面级(指猎鹰9号的二级)的大小与整个新谢泼德航天器相当
But let's give credit where credit is due 100% here
但是 让我们在这里百分之百地给予赞扬吧
because this is no easy feat.
因为这不是一个简单的壮举
And it's still easily one of the coolest things a rocket can do, period.
而且反推式着陆依然是一枚火箭能做到的最酷的事情之一 真的
You may also notice that the booster has a ring that the capsule sits on top of.
你可能还注意到 太空舱坐在助推器的环上面
I love this design
我喜欢这个设计
because not only does it serve a purpose for aerodynamic stability during re-entry,
因为它不仅有助于提高再入大气时的空气动力学稳定性
but it also has reliefs for the abort motor.
而且 还为中止发动机提供了排气槽
This means if they had to light the abort motor while attached to the booster,
这意味着如果太空舱在连接到助推器上的时候必须要点燃中止发动机
there's a place for that hot gas to go
仍然有空间留给中止发动机排出的热气
lessening the chance of the solid rocket motor exploding the booster below it.
减少了固体火箭发动机摧毁其下助推器的可能性
As a matter of fact, they did exactly that for an in-flight abort test
事实上 在那次飞行中中止测试里
when they lit that abort motor, while it was still on top of the booster.
当他们点燃那个中止发动机时 太空舱仍然在助推器上面
And miraculously quite literally, I think to everyone's surprise, not only did the booster survive,
而且奇迹般地 我觉得每个人都感到惊讶的是 不仅助推器存活了下来
it actually still came back and landed softly, which was absolutely incredible.
它实际上还是回来了 并轻轻地着陆了 这绝对是不可思议的
Okay, now back to the capsule that of course has the passengers on board.
好了 那么回到太空舱 当然 太空舱上有乘客
So the booster pushes it up towards space
所以助推器把它推向太空
and let's go off the capsule shortly after it shuts its engines down.
并在它关闭发动机后不久放开太空舱
Then both the booster and the capsule will coast up to peak altitude or apogee,
然后助推器和太空舱都会滑行到最高高度或者远地点
and then they both will begin to fall back down.
然后它们都将开始落下
The capsule will return slower than the booster though,
不过太空舱的返回速度会比助推器慢
thanks to its larger surface area and blunt body design.
由于其较大的表面积和钝体设计
Since it has humans onboard,
由于太空舱载人
it uses a tried and true system parachutes.
它使用一个久经考验的降落伞系统
At about two kilometers it deploys three drogue chutes
在大约2km的高度 它展开了三个引导降落伞
followed by three main chutes at just about one kilometer in altitude.
然后在大约1km的高度上展开三个主降落伞
Now, despite the capsule coming down super, super slow, it only about 25 kilometers an hour
那么 尽管太空舱降落的速度超级超级慢 只有大约6.9m/s
they make the touchdown even softer
他们让太空舱的触地变得更加轻柔
by firing some retro thrusters at the very last moment to create a nice cushion of air.
通过在最后时刻点燃一些反向推进器来创造一个漂亮的气垫
You might notice a bunch of dust getting kicked up right as it lands.
你可能会注意到在它着陆时有一堆灰尘被吹起
That's not coming down hard.
这并不意味着降落得很重
That's it coming down so soft and just gliding on a nice little cushion of air.
(实际上)它降落时非常柔软 只是在一个漂亮的小气垫上滑行
It's similar to what the Soyuz capsule does when it's touching down too.
这与联盟号太空舱着陆时的情况类似
It helps absorb energy before hitting the ground.
它有助于在落地前吸收能量
And what's crazy is the New Shepard could actually lose two of its three main parachutes
而最疯狂的是 新谢泼德号实际上可以失去其三个主降落伞中的两个
and still land slowly enough to be able to be survivable.
但仍能缓慢着陆 以便能够存活
And that's also thanks to shock absorbing seats.
而这也要感谢减震座椅
Unlike SpaceShipTwo, in fact, completely opposite of SpaceShipTwo,
与太空船二号不同 事实上 与太空船二号完全相反
New Shepard is 100% autonomous.
新谢泼德是100%自主控制的
This means all 6 seats on board can be filled with passengers
这意味着船上的所有6个座位都可以坐满乘客
and there is no need for any of those seats to be taken up by pilots.
而不需要任何一个座位被飞行员占用
And each of the six passengers are treated to massive windows.
而且 每名乘客都可以看到巨大的窗户
In fact, they are the largest windows to ever fly to space,
事实上 它们是有史以来飞往太空的最大窗户
which would definitely be important
这肯定是很重要的
when the entire purpose of this flight is to see some incredible views that you've never seen before.
当这次飞行的全部目的是为了看到一些前从未见的惊人景色时
New Shepherd successfully flew 15 times before putting humans on board.
新谢泼德在载人发射之前成功地飞行了15次
They lost their first booster on their first attempt in early 2015,
他们在2015年初的第一次尝试中失去了第一个助推器
but safely recovered their capsule.
但安全地回收了太空舱
Then the second booster would fly five times before being retired.
然后第二个助推器在退役前飞了五次
The third booster and second capsule flew seven times successively before being retired
第三个助推器和第二个太空舱连续飞行了七次才退役
and then the fourth booster and the third capsule flew twice
然后第四个助推器和第三个太空舱飞了两次
before being ready to be the first to fly humans now.
之后准备成为第一个载人发射的组合体
Okay, I think that about does it for New Shepherd.
好了 我想新谢泼德的情况大概就是这样了
Now let's put these two vehicles up side by side and compare their exact specs.
那么让我们把这两个航天器并排放在一起 比较它们的确切规格
并排比较
Okay. Let's get these two vehicles up side by side
好的 让我们把这两个航天器并排放在一起
so we can get a sense of just how big they actually are.
这样我们就能感觉到它们实际上有多大
SpaceShipTwo is 18 meters long with an 8.2 meter wingspan and a tail height of 4.6 meters.
太空船二号长18米 翼展8.2米 尾高4.6米
It's about as long as New Shepard is tall,
它的长度和新谢泼德的高度差不多
which is 19 meters tall and about 3.8 meters wide.
而新谢泼德为19米高 大约3.8米宽
And just for fun, let's throw in a Falcon 9 for scale too,
为了好玩 让我们把猎鹰9号也扔进去 对比下尺寸
which helps give you a sense of perspective.
这能给你一个合理的认知
Falcon 9 towers over these vehicles with its 70 meter height.
猎鹰9号以其70米的高度耸立在这些航天器之上
Next their engines, which we're showing their propellant and cycle types
接下来是他们的发动机 我们展示了他们的推进剂和循环类型
along with their thrust and efficiency measured in seconds of specific impulse,
以及它们的推力和效率 也就是以秒为单位的比冲
Blue Origin's BE-3 definitely has an impressive thrust and specific impulse.
蓝色起源的BE-3有一个绝对令人印象深刻的推力和比冲
The burn time of these engines is quite different
这些发动机的燃烧时间是相当不同的
due to the fact that New Shepard launches on the ground and SpaceShipTwo launches mid air.
由于新谢泼德号是在地面上发射的 而太空船二号是在空中发射的
发动机燃烧时间应该和推重比的关系更大，太空船二号的初始推重比应该有3左右，
新谢泼德初始推重比约为1.47，参考 en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SpaceShipTwo#Specifications，
flightclub.io/result/2d?id=06a1c3be-df3a-4595-b848-5ab7e00a6fb9
Because of this New Shepherd's BE-3 runs for aboruaut two minutes and 20 seconds or so
正因为如此 新谢泼德的BE-3大约运行了2分20秒左右
compared to just about one minute for SpaceShipTwo.
相比之下 太空船二号只用了大约一分钟
I should probably point out here that the hydrolox running New Shepard is very clean burning
我也许应该在这里指出 运行新谢泼德的液氢液氧的燃烧是非常清洁的
and has very very little environmental impacts since its by-product is just water vapor.
而且对环境的影响非常非常小 因为其副产品只是水蒸气
But that same thing can't really be said for SpaceshipTwo's solid rocket propellant,
但是对于太空船二号的固体推进剂来说 就不是这样了
which is pretty nasty, especially for the ozone layer.
其燃烧产物是不太好的 特别是对臭氧层而言
Now that said it's really comparable per passenger to a transatlantic flight.
尽管如此 单位乘客的排放量也就是和横跨大西洋的航空飞行是一个水平
youtu.be/C4VHfmiwuv4
If you need a deep rundown on what exactly comes out of rockets
如果你需要深入了解火箭到底产生了什么
and what impact they have on our environment, definitely watch this video.
以及它们对我们的环境有什么影响 一定要看这个视频
It's a super, super deep dive on that topic.
这个视频对这个主题进行了深入的研究
As we mentioned, SpaceShipTwo can carry eight people, two pilots and six passengers
正如我们所提到的太空船二号可以搭载8人 2名飞行员和6名乘客
and New Shepard can carry six passengers.
而新谢泼德号可以搭载六名乘客
Next total flight time from takeoff to landing.
接下来从起飞到降落的总飞行时间
New Shepard is a much shorter ride.
新谢泼德的旅程要短得多
Only about 10 minutes from takeoff to landing
从起飞到着陆只有大约10分钟
whereas SpaceShipTwo's usual flight time is about two hours from wheels up to touchdown.
而太空船二号的通常飞行时间从起飞到着陆大约是两个小时
But a lot of that time is either the long slow climb up while being attached to WhiteKnightTwo,
但其中很多时间是花在与白骑士二号相连时缓慢爬升的漫长过程
or the slow glide back down.
以及缓慢地滑翔回来
Both vehicles still end up spending roughly the same amount of time experiencing zero G of around four minutes.
在失重体验的那一部分 两种航天器花费的时间大致相同
But one notable difference between the two vehicles is their maximum altitude.
但这两个航天器的一个明显区别是其最大高度
The highest VSS unity has ever flown is just shy of 90 kilometers,
VSS团结号所飞过的最高高度仅略低于90km
which does mean it has never crossed the Karman line,
这确实意味着它从未越过卡门线
although it's frankly arbitrary
尽管卡门线的定义是很随意的
and doesn't really change anything as far as your experience goes,
就你的体验而言 并没有真正改变什么
it is worth noting.
但这是值得注意的
A New Shepherd on the other hand does cross the Karman line and has an apogee of about 105 kilometers.
另一方面 新谢泼德确实跨越了卡门线 其远地点约为105km
Another fun and really important to note about these systems is that they are both fully reusable.
关于这些系统的另一个有趣且重要的是 它们都是可完全重复使用的
I think this is vital in bringing the costs down.
我认为这对降低成本至关重要
I can't imagine the cost if they were throwing away hardware each and every launch,
我无法想象如果他们每次发射都扔掉设备的花费
which brings us to the price.
谈到这个 就顺便提提价格问题
Now this isn't something that's actually really that well published yet.
现在 这个问题实际上还没有被很好地公布
We do know most people who have paid for rides on SpaceShipTwo have paid $250,000,
我们确实知道 大多数购买太空船二号船票的人都支付了25万美元
but unfortunately we don't really know what's the price of a ride on New Shepherd.
但不幸的是 我们并不知道乘坐新谢泼德的价格是多少
There's really been only one example of price so far,
到目前为止 真正有价格的例子只有一个
and it's a customer who bid $28 million to fly on the first flight
而那是一个客户出价2800万美元 乘坐新谢泼德首航
alongside Jeff Bezos, his brother Mark and aviation legend, Wally Funk.
首航人员还包括杰夫·贝佐斯 他的兄弟马克 以及航空业传奇人物沃利·芬克
But I think it's safe to assume the standard price will be much closer to that $250, 000 mark,
但我认为可以安全地假设 标准价格将更接近25万美元的大关
similar to SpaceShipTwo.
与太空船二号类似
Although some sources have reported, it might actually be significantly higher,
虽然有些消息来源报道 实际上可能会大大高于这个价格
but I guess we'll just have to wait and see.
但我想我们只能拭目以待
But that about does it for the rundown of these two awesome suborbital vehicles.
但是 关于这两个了不起的亚轨道航天器的介绍就到此为止了
All right. I think it's time for a summary.
好了 我想是时候做个总结了
总结
I just love that we're at a time
我只是喜欢我们处于这样一个时代
when there's two wildly different solutions for suborbital spaceflight tourism,
同时存在两种截然不同的亚轨道太空旅游的方案
and they're going online at almost the exact same time.
而且它们几乎在同一时间上线
Both systems are honestly beautiful in their own way.
老实说 这两个系统都有其独特的美
I love the safety redundancy and simplicity of Blue Origins, traditional capsule based New Shepard.
我喜欢蓝色起源的安全冗余和简单性 以及基于传统太空舱的新谢泼德
But at the same time, I love the elegant and beautiful solution with air launching
但与此同时 我也喜欢空中发射的优雅和美丽的解决方案
and feathered re-entry like Virgin Galactic spaceship.
以及像维珍银河太空船那样的羽翼再入
As far as which one would I rather ride on though?
至于我会乘坐哪一个？
That's really hard to answer, sincerely.
这真的很难回答 实话说
I think before Virgin Galactic showed off their interior, I really wasn't that interested.
我想在维珍银河展示他们的内饰之前 我真的不是很感兴趣
But once I saw that gorgeous interior, those awesome seats,
但是一旦我看到那华丽的内饰 那些令人赞叹的座椅
the attention to detail on the lightings and cameras and just the whole thing,
对灯光和摄像机之类的细节的关注 以及整个飞船(的独特设计)
I really could finally picture myself riding on it.
我终于可以想象自己乘坐它的情景了
I also liked the idea of it being a longer flight.
对于其飞行时间更长这一点 我也喜欢
After all, even the ride is still attached to WhiteKnightTwo would be pretty amazing
毕竟 即使是连接着白骑士二号的飞行 也是相当惊人的
and the slow glide back down from space seems pretty fun as well.
而从太空中缓慢滑翔回来的过程似乎也很有趣
You might as well soak up as much time as possible in that seat since you paid for it.
既然付了钱 你不妨在那个座位上尽可能多花时间感受
I also really liked how the spaceship oriented itself to look back down on earth
我还非常喜欢太空船对姿态的调整 这样就能从地球上空往下看
so you can look straight down.
这样你就可以直接向下看
I think that's really cool.
我认为这真的很酷
But I'm blown away and honestly,
但说实话 我有点扫兴
half annoyed at how cautiously Blue Origin has developed New Shepard.
特别是对蓝色起源开发新谢泼德时的谨慎态度感到有点生气
I mean, it's obviously for the better
当然了 更慢的节奏显然是为了更好地发展
and I'd have a lot of confidence riding on a vehicle
而且我对乘坐这样的交通工具很有信心
that has had such absolute stringent testing regime with 15 successful uncrewed flights.
毕竟有着如此严格的测试制度 以及15次成功的无人飞行
Not to mention, I love the fact that New Shepard has a lot of redundancy
更不用说 我喜欢新谢泼德具备的大量冗余能力
and a full envelope launch abort system.
以及一个涵盖完整飞行包线的发射中止系统
And I love those massive, massive windows on New Shepard.
我还喜欢新谢泼德号上那些巨大的窗户
But at the end of the day, I think both systems seem to offer just an amazing ride.
那么最后 我认为这两个系统似乎都提供了一个惊人的旅程
And they've both focused on the customer getting a really incredible experience
而且他们都专注于让客户获得一个真正令人难以置信的体验
and I'd probably hop on the opportunity to ride on either system in a heartbeat.
而我可能会抓住机会 立刻乘坐这两个系统
And I can only hope that in the future,
我只希望 在未来
we might all get to experience something as incredible as these rides.
我们都能体验到像这样不可思议的旅程
I mean, imagine if the price came down enough
我是指 想象一下 如果价格下降到
that it'd be similar to like skydiving or some other really fun experience.
与跳伞或者其他非常有趣的体验相似的程度
You just go take a quick little ride to space.
你就能快速而短暂地前往太空
Wouldn't that be incredible.
岂不美哉
So what do you think?
那么你怎么想？
when you ride on either of these vehicles, both of them,
neither of them do you think we'll see long-term commercial success
and this is just the start of a new era of commercial spaceflight,
or do you think this is not going to last,
let me know your thoughts and questions in the comments below.
I owe a huge thank you to my patreon supporters for making this video
and everything else that we do here at Everyday Astronaut possible.
You can show your support and also gain access to some fun perks,
like becoming part of our incredible discord community or getting access to exclusive live streams.
And you also can get early access to videos and scripts as well,
where you can share your thoughts and feedback before the video comes out,
head on over to patreon.com/everydayastronaut while you're online.
Be sure and check out our amazing web store where you can find shirts like this,
the awesome F1 t-shirt, you know,
kind of one of the coolest engines and most important engines ever made,
but you can find lots of really cool merchandise like our full flow staged combustion cycle hoodie
and shirt or our future Martian collection or Aerospike collection.
Lots of really fun stuff for you and your family or anyone that just loves space.
Go to everydayastronaut.com/shop.
Thanks everybody. That's going to do it for me.
谢谢大家观看 本期节目到这里就结束了
I'm Tim Dodd, the everyday astronaut,
我是Tim Dodd 每日宇航员
bringing space down to Earth, for everyday people.
将太空的知识带给地球上的普通人